<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>FraLab</title>
<link>https:/tester/blogs.html</link>
<atom:link href="https:/tester/blogs.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Our first attempt at semi-regular blog posts.</description>
<image>
<url>https:/tester/img/BlogBanner2.jpeg</url>
<title>FraLab</title>
<link>https:/tester/blogs.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.4.551</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Carbon-I proposal to NASA’s ESE call</title>
  <dc:creator>Christian Frankenberg</dc:creator>
  <link>https:/tester/BlogPosts/Carbon-I.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="nasas-ese-call" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="nasas-ese-call">NASA’s ESE call</h2>
<p>NASA’s <a href="https://explorers.larc.nasa.gov/2023ESE/">Earth System Explorer</a> call solicits Principal Investigator (PI)-led space science investigations as recommended by The National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine 2017 Decadal Survey for Earth Science and Applications from Space. Greenhouse gases were specifically mentioned a high priority. Thus, we put a proposal into the ring again, following years of work on high-spatial resolution greenhouse gas mapping, a journey that started with initial AVIRIS-NG measurements, the first ever controlled release experiments using aircrafts, large-scale mapping of the anomalous CH<sub>4</sub> enhancements in the Four-Corners region, and now with the success of EMIT.</p>
</section>
<section id="carbon-i" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="carbon-i">Carbon-I</h2>
<p><img src="https://carbon-i.github.io/img/Logo-Black2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><a href="https://carbon-i.github.io/">Carbon-I</a> is our response to NASA’s ESE call, it can be considered a merger of the philosophies behind the original OCO mission and the high resolution mapping approaches that are now followed by EMIT, GHGSat, CarbonMapper, MethaneSat and others. We are eagerly awaiting a decision from NASA in April and are ready to hit the ground running. What could Carbon-I bring to the table? The combination of high spatial resolution and high enough spectral resolution for trace gas mapping solves two problems:</p>
<ol type="I">
<li>We will obtain enough data in the tropics, which has been a major problem for OCO-2, TROPOMI and other missions, mostly because shallow cumulus clouds have cloud gaps that are much smaller than the footprint size of current greenhouse gas sensors. This leads to periods of <strong>data drought</strong> in the humid tropics <a href="https://essopenarchive.org/users/528524/articles/717473-data-drought-in-the-humid-tropics-how-to-overcome-the-cloud-barrier-in-greenhouse-gas-remote-sensing">Pre-print paper</a>: <img src="https:/tester/img/blogs/clouds.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></li>
<li>It will avoid surface interferences, that plagues high-spatial-resolution mappers with coarse spectral resolution.</li>
</ol>
<p>We have a great team and are doing something <strong>different</strong> with Carbon-I. The greenhouse gas remote sensing field is getting crowded, both on the agency side targetting high accuracy for flux inversions (OCO-2, OCO-3, GOSAT, GOSAT-2, GOSAT-GW, TROPOMI, Sentinel-5, CO2M, etc) as well as the plume mapping side to provide actionable results (EMIT, GHGSat, MethaneSat, CarbonMapper). Carbon-I aims to tackle the issue those missions can’t resolve by merging their advantages…</p>
</section>
<section id="a-carbon-i-website" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-carbon-i-website">A Carbon-I website…</h2>
<p>Why create a website for something that isn’t even funded yet? Honestly, Quarto makes this a lot more fun and provides an ideal system for scientists to run their own website, and describe science in fun interactive ways. <a href="https://carbon-i.github.io/">Carbon-I</a> is still very rudimentary but creating some interactive graphics with ObservableJS has been fun, even though I <strong>dislike</strong> java script syntax. So it has been absolutely worth it and we learned a lot along the way…</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Greenhouse Gases</category>
  <category>Spectroscopy</category>
  <category>Satellite mission</category>
  <category>Remote Sensing</category>
  <guid>https:/tester/BlogPosts/Carbon-I.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://carbon-i.github.io/img/Logo-Black2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Website Update using Quarto</title>
  <dc:creator>Christian Frankenberg</dc:creator>
  <link>https:/tester/BlogPosts/BlogQuarto.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="why-a-new-website" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="why-a-new-website">Why a new website</h2>
<p>When I first started my faculty job, I created my own website but coded most of the tools myself, which looked fun but was incredibly hard to maintain. Unsurprisingly, I hadn’t changed my website for more than 3 years and eveything became outdated. My group members, esp.&nbsp;Yiwei Mao, Yinon Bar-On and Alexis Renchon showed me new tools and suggested to use Quarto. Lots of nice examples from <em><a href="https://affcom.ku.edu/">Affcom Lab</a></em> , <em><a href="https://github.com/CrumpLab/CrumpLab.github.io">Crump Lab</a></em> , and <em><a href="https://github.com/gilmore-lab/gilmore-lab.github.io/tree/master/src">Gilmore Lab</a></em> showed me it could be done and will save time <em>eventually</em>.</p>
</section>
<section id="why-quarto" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="why-quarto">Why Quarto?</h2>
<p><a href="https://quarto.org/">Quarto</a> seems to be able to do many things I am interested in, not only rendering nice websites but also notebooks and code itself, esp.&nbsp;in <a href="https://julialang.org">Julia</a>. What is most important to me in a website is that I can make more regular updates without changing HTML sites, change group members, keep track of alumni, provide news. The system of using MarkDown language and easy setup files looked quite appealing to me and we gave it a try.</p>
</section>
<section id="how-is-it-going" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="how-is-it-going">How is it going</h2>
<p>We have made decent progress but lots more work to do. Suggestions are always welcome!</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https:/tester/BlogPosts/BlogQuarto.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
